If you have high performing staff that
are deciding to leave the company or
they're being forced out of the company
because of them just feeling like they
just can't anymore, then that's when the
company ends up losing a ton of money
when they could have just invested it
properly in their team in the first
place. And that will again keep
happening over and over until the
leaders at the top start making more
financial decisions and how to support
the team. It it seems and feels like a
responsible financial decision, but in
actuality, they're not actually looking
at the entire cost. I've seen that sadly
too many times as well. Carly, welcome
to the Signal Room.
Thank you. Happy to be here.
I'm so excited to talk to you today. It,
you know, we've had a couple
conversations and it's remarkable. Turns
out we've known, you know, some people
in common and actually one of them was
on on the show a while ago and uh as we
spoke the other day, I was like
fascinated hearing about what you're
doing. It's very timely and very
relevant. uh as we kind of talked about
the fact that we are in a really
interesting transition or
transformational period with all the
stuff going on with AI and I think we're
probably getting because it's moving so
quickly we're we're losing track of some
things that are kind of important and
really starts with people and
relationships which obviously is your
area of expertise. So I'd love for you
to just just talk a little bit about
what you're what you're doing. I mean, I
know you're you're doing a lot of great
coaching and yeah, you're you're
supporting executive teams, but there's
a lot more to it. And I I just love to
have you talk about that a little bit.
Then we'll dig into some of the things
that that you're seeing that are
concerning and what can we do about it.
Sure. Well, you know, it it kind of
reminds me because I was just talking to
a friend of mine who is an AI expert and
she is also a previous client of mine
and she said, you know, Carly, I think
your job is actually AI proof. And I
said to her, "What makes you say that?"
And she said, 'Well, thinking about AI,
there's nothing can that can replace a
real coach. And I've thought about this
a lot. You know, there's a lot of people
who try to use AI for coaching, for
counseling, for any sort of advice
giving, and it's just not the same.
So, I thought what she said was
brilliant, and it makes me think about
kind of your question of what I do. what
I do is is partially what AI can't. I
look at people for who they are and can
listen to their emotions and empathize
with them and that is something that is
being taken away by AI.
That's a huge huge point there. I mean
it doesn't really even listen to you. I
mean we talk about you know things like
ambient listening but it's there's it
doesn't interpret things the way that an
human beings is going to interpret it.
Um it's not going to pick up body
language. It's not going to feel
anything. I mean that's a really
significant thing. I I think we need we
probably need what you do a lot more
than we have ever needed it to be
honest.
Well, I mean I think if you look at it,
people are constantly wanting to feel
seen and heard. That's just a normal
part of being human. And so while we can
look to technology to help us in certain
times where we don't have another human
next to us, there's also just so much
benefit to having that other person
there. So, what I'm trying to do is be
there for leaders. And it doesn't matter
what organization or what kind of field
we're talking about, no matter what kind
of leader they are, that implies that
they're having a ripple effect on their
entire team. And if their team doesn't
know how to regulate their own nervous
system and they're just being run ragged
by whatever system they're working in,
then that's exactly where coaching can
fit in. And so I think when we think
about people's sustainability of working
in a job and why a lot of people are
unhappy, a lot of it has to do with the
fact that they're not even given the
tools to be able to regulate their own
stress and there's not enough importance
being put on that now because it's just
kind of
the norm that you're just given one more
thing to do and expected to do it
because you're a high performer.
Yeah. And I I think we've not done
ourselves a lot of favors in the last
several years. And we've gotten even
more dependent on technology and
unfortunately there's just this layer
with social media between people when
you know some of these basic concepts
are just they're being largely ignored
and people don't even realize the kind
of deficits they actually have. It's
really important for someone to be able
to talk about this and make sure that
you know leadership teams are
understanding what people are really
going for. Um I think there's probably a
a disconnect and it's one of the things
I was wanted to hear hear you talk about
today is the workforce reality gap.
There is this disconnect between how
leadership defines workforce stability
and how the front line actually
experiences it. Um I think there's so
many layers in between. I don't know
where it all gets lost, but I I think
there's there's definitely an issue that
that we need to talk about there. It
needs to be brought to the forefront, I
think, sooner than later.
I think what's missing is a conversation
because you can do all the surveys you
want, all the staff satisfaction
metrics. You can look at those and they
can look good on the surface, but then
you actually talk to a frontline worker,
you talk to somebody who's working in a
hospital and they might have a
completely different take on what it
means to be fully staffed. So leadership
from a from their perspective, they
might think, okay, we're in a good
place, we're fully staffed. And then you
talk to somebody on the front line and
they they're going to say, are you
kidding me? This is this is what fully
staffed is. And I've talked to people
too who work in healthcare who say that
they've never even heard anybody say
we're fully staffed in the nursing field
specifically because they're constantly
being bombarded with new things to do,
new layers. You add in AI and the
technology that they need to use in in
everyday interactions with their
patients that they didn't have to use
before. And while some of that is good
because it can create more time, in
other cases, and depending on the
person, if they're just one step away
from feeling so burnt out that they're
leaving, adding in more technology might
actually do more harm than good,
right? Now, you know, burned out of one
of those words we're hearing a lot more,
particularly in the healthcare space
with nursing and and physicians. to your
your point, you touched on something
that, you know, just reminds me of how
how you what you do is actually so
unique and and how you actually work
with executives cuz you talk about
interacting with with some of the staff.
We talk a little bit about that if you
would. I mean, I think that that's an
interesting thing and I and I'm hoping
that as our our listeners are hearing
this conversation, it maybe inspires
them to think about how, you know, they
could actually be uh getting some
support in areas that maybe they don't
realize they can get.
Well, I think just kind of backing up to
to looking at a Gallup poll. The Gallup
poll last year said that about 20% of
people are actually engaged in their
job. 20%. So that means 80% are
somewhere somewhere on the other end of
the spectrum. And so when you combine
those numbers of where everybody sits on
the chart, it can look pretty good. You
know, if there are a lot of people who
are putting a seven or eight on the
scale and then you've got a bunch of
people that are putting a two on the
scale, it's going to even out. And
unless you have the right people in
leadership who are actually going to be
smart enough and not just look at the
results as an aggregate but kind of
drill down into okay what are these 20%
of people saying what are they
experiencing? I think I think with even
with surveys or with the way that we are
kind of interacting with each other
nowadays we oftentimes just look at
people as not even people. We look at
them as kind of units that are working
for us in, you know, in a spot in our
budget and we don't remember that they
actually have a whole lot of thoughts,
feelings, beliefs that they're dealing
with every day in addition to the
struggles of being a human. And so until
we kind of give people credit where
credit is due and see them for who they
are,
that's going to just keep continuing.
that number is going to keep at 20%
until we actually start to have
conversations with people to say, "How
can we make your job actually better?"
And burnout is contagious, too. If there
are people on your team that are a step
away from leaving, then it's going to
infect the whole team dynamic. And so,
part of what I'm doing with teams and
part of my belief about all of this is
that you really need to look at the
individual in order to affect team
culture. If people don't have the tools
to be able to regulate their own stress
individually, then the whole team is not
going to have the tools to regulate
their stress as a team. And with
coaching, with being able to kind of
bring it back to honestly the most human
basics that one could even think about,
like breathing is one of them. Breathing
is the tool that's using our own body.
That's the most basic software that we
have and everybody has it installed
already. We don't need to learn
something or go listen to something or
go read a new book in order to
understand how our lungs can work. But
there are so many people that you talk
to that say, "Oh yeah, breathing, yes, I
know if I take deep breaths, whatever,
it'll calm me down." but they don't
actually put that into practice when it
could be the the kind of deciding factor
between them being able to feel calm and
collected before a meeting or them
feeling like they're spiraling out of
control. So going back to some of the
basics of what we've already got with
our human nature to be able to say,
"Hey, let's tap into this and let's
actually activate it and have some
accountability and do it in a group
setting with other members of our team."
What I've seen in working with folks is
that it's the the results are just
exponential. The burnout goes away.
People feel more satisfied. people
understand why they're doing the work
and why it's important and why they are
important in that particular
organization. And so I think unless
there's some kind of mechanisms or
systems put into place for people
people's leadership to improve then it's
going to just be a problem that
proliferates over and over again with
people's dissatisfaction in their
workplace.
That's a that's a powerful realization
when people are oftenimes not even aware
of some of the stresses and anxieties
that they're carrying and how it's
impacting them. And you know if there's
not a some point where somebody's able
to have that conversation with them like
you described, you know, a group setting
like that, they are not even likely
aware of just exactly how how close to
burnout they are. And then all of a
sudden just some easy conversation from
someone who knows how to do this. It
just unlocks this the the stress and
they they feel that that released and
it's not it's not like some sort of a
magic drug or something. It's just, you
know, something that is simple as
remembering to breathe. And, you know,
it seems like an odd thing to say, but
um I've I've experienced that the
challenge with that on my own a few
different times. And you know, it's I
would have appreciated particularly
during the pandemic if as someone that
was really thinking about that because I
would have probably tried to help my own
teams a lot more than I than I knew to,
you know, going through that period.
There's a point that you you you ted on
there and really about it's this the
design uh concept and know we're talking
about design in in in the context of
technology and systems a lot you know
like AI but what at what point does a
staffing problem actually become a a
system design problem because I think
what you're describing there's some
systemic things that have to be in place
long before you can introduce
technology.
This reminds me of a conversation I had
last week because part of what I do is I
also talk to CEOs and other senior
leaders in organizations in order to get
a read on what's happening in different
types of organizations. And one of them
said to me, "Yeah, in in my circles with
other leaders that I talked to, they
don't care at all about firing people.
They just say, "Okay, how fast can we
get them out so we can get somebody else
in?" And that's how they look at the
human. And so what happens is they end
up replacing the human, which is
extremely expensive, extremely expensive
to find somebody else to get them
onboarded. You've got institutional
knowledge that just walked out the door.
So you're bringing somebody else in and
starting from zero.
So by replacing somebody, you're
actually having a huge impact
financially on the organization and they
just don't care. And that last part is
what is the really important part. Where
is the care? Where is the care about the
human person? Because we can keep
replacing the people into these roles,
but what's going to happen? They're
going to burn out too. And so that's to
me when it becomes a systems problem
when you know you've got multiple people
either on the same team or within the
same role that all decide to leave, it's
a leadership issue. There's a there's a
lot of people out there who have really
poor leaders and the leaders might have
gotten there because they're good at
their technical skill. Like maybe they
are a good doctor so they end up rising
in the ranks or maybe they're a good
plumber so they rise up in the ranks.
But just because you're good at what you
do doesn't mean you're a good leader of
people. And I think that that's where
the design part needs to be looked at a
lot more closely because if you have
high performing staff that are deciding
to leave the company or they're being
forced out of the company because of
them just feeling like they just can't
anymore,
then then that's when the company ends
up losing a ton of money when they could
have just invested it properly in their
team in the first place. And that will
again keep happening over and over until
people start the leaders at the top
start making more um sound financial
decisions and how to support the team.
Yeah. I mean it seems and feels like a
responsible financial decision, but in
actuality they're not actually looking
at the the entire cost thing. That's I'
I've seen that sadly too many times as
well. There's there's this other gap
thinking you you you touched on too.
It's like a lot of organizations that
I've interacted with over the years have
a um have a real challenge in terms of
having career ladders uh for people who
are really solid individual contributors
uh particularly when you get into
technical roles but I think it's
probably true in a lot of different ways
but there's this practice that uh for
better for worse mostly worse probably
where people the only option to advance
their career is to give them oversight
responsibilities or managerial responsib
abilities, but often times we're not
really teaching them some really basic
things about what a human being actually
needs in the workforce. And I don't
think I've ever had that kind of
conversation uh outside of something
that was really deliberate, at least set
up for me from a coaching standpoint,
just one-on-one.
It's a really great thing that you can
see that because a lot of people can't.
A lot of people will say, "Oh, everybody
here is fine and our organization's
thriving." you know, they can see they
track things via numbers. So, if the
profits are looking good, they think the
people are good. And that's where
there's a huge mistake being made
because they're not again looking at the
people for people. A lot of times people
will talk about not being able to be
their full selves when they walk into
work and they've got to leave some of
their identities behind and nobody likes
to feel that way. And so what you're
talking about with the managerial gap
that causes a lot of imposttor syndrome
in people and they start to feel even if
they do get promoted because of a
technical you know a technical
proficiency that they have they don't
get the managerial training and then
they end up feeling like they're not
good enough and then they start
questioning why did I get this promotion
in the first place and then they end up
walking out the door because they don't
feel like they were actually up to snuff
on the job that they were doing. Again,
this is something that in hindsight, if
the organization actually valued people
whenever people got promoted, they
should get a coach. In my opinion, and
I'm here to say my opinion, so that's my
opinion. They should get a coach and
they should get quality managerial
training because you cannot just throw
somebody into the deep end um when
they've got a promotion if they've got
other people underneath them. It is a
huge gap in training and development of
leaders.
Yeah, I I I've worked with a couple of
different organizations that have I
think done a pretty decent job of really
putting some things in place, you know,
identifying, you know, people who they
they think are uh you know, potential
candidates for for leadership roles.
It's not consistent across
any industries that that I've seen, but
there are some that do a reasonably good
job of at least identifying people that
have potential in giving them
opportunities to to get this kind of
training before they throw them into the
the deep end of the pool. But it it it
is a big gap and it's so important
because the first layer of oversight is
where we probably have the biggest risks
because we have people who are having
the they're in these really public
facing roles. I mean they're interacting
with people, you know, one-on-one uh
large scale whether it's retail,
whatever industry we're talking about.
These people need support. They need
someone to that actually understands
what they need and actually can really
help them navigate things on a
day-to-day basis. It's not just enough
to be able to tell them what to do, what
not to do, or get, you know, call them
on making mistakes. I mean, there's just
basic human support that needs that that
we have. I mean, what are you seeing in
terms of the the the levels where, you
know, these things are are so critically
out of out of whack? Uh the what do we
do about it? and and because I don't
even know that people understand what
we're what we're doing to frontline
staff sometimes.
It's a great question. I think the
answer for me is people tend to kind of
look at this backwards of they tend to
cut leadership development when budgets
get tight. And that's the exact opposite
that should be done. If you have a
company, for example, that has a mass
layoff, there are people still left
standing at that company that lost their
friends that are no longer working
there, might have lost their supervisor,
depending on who got laid off,
regardless of who got cut in whatever
the layoff was, the people who remain
standing there now, their psychological
safety is completely under threat.
They're they're now going home every day
wondering if they should look for new
jobs. They're wondering if the day is
going to come where their name is next
on the chopping block and their stress
level is going to go through the roof.
So, while people are thinking about
layoffs, if that's actually on the
table, they should also be thinking
about what are we doing to support the
people who are still going to be here at
this company. Because you can't put a
line item on the cost of somebody not
knowing how to have a com a hard
conversation with their employees
or the cost of a team not trusting its
leadership or the cost of three people
who decide to leave because they just
can't handle their boss anymore or can't
handle the workload anymore.
Right? and all of that it it goes so
undetected because on exit interviews or
even on the staff satisfaction surveys
people don't feel like they can be
honest. They they are fearful now
because of what has happened in this
country and in the industry and know
that if they want to continue working
there, they've got to keep quiet and
keep drowning in their own misery. And
that is so dangerous. And when we talk
about the healthcare industry, it's so
dangerous because then your staff
satisfaction is now bleeding into your
patient care. And if people are feeling
overloaded and like they're not feeling
supported and like they just are running
on fumes, then that's the energy that
the patients are going to pick up on
and they're going to feel more rushed
when they're dealing with the patients
because of that exact thing that they
have numbers to meet. They have targets
to hit. They're short staffed. Their
leaders are saying, "Okay, well, we just
are going to be x number of people short
staffed today and we just need to keep
going." They don't they don't get a pay
raise. they don't get a pat on the back
even. It's just kind of the way it is.
And so burnout doesn't happen overnight.
Burnout happens from chronic stress that
goes unnoticed for a long time or goes
unressed either by the person
individually or the organization.
Yeah. You you mentioned the service. I
you know I I had a really great team
that I that I was privileged to work
with when I was in New York. And one of
the things that you know we talked about
with with with my my management team
when we're looking at the surveys I mean
yeah it's great when you get you know
that the high marks but but we're
looking at the of course we look at that
we want to celebrate the good things but
then we look at the areas where we we
have some real significant things to
work on. Um sometimes we had to like
almost invent them which was surprising
because people were were actually giving
us really good feedback and and we just
were you there was there's three of us
that work for actually three different
bosses but we just put our we put
everything together to so that we could
collectively really try to manage um a
function regardless of who reported to
who. But we just wanted to make sure
that we're paying attention and we're
we're supporting the team. What the area
that I tend to tended to spend the most
time on was the middle the road stuff
and primarily because if we're not doing
enough to even move the needle that's a
problem and we're just you know we're
just one mistake away from
it, you know, hitting a hitting a bump
because, you know, we're we're just not
motivating people the right way. We're
not paying attention to something. I I
mean I don't really hear a lot about
that, but I think there's probably a lot
of that. And maybe talk about what what
you think the perception is for for an
executive that's reading their
engagement scores versus what the
reality is from what you see on the
ground. I mean, maybe talk about some of
this stuff that just seems to be hidden
and not moving the needle enough. Yeah,
I'm smiling because I think that we just
have to use common sense because we all
have probably filled out a staff
satisfaction survey where we haven't
told the full truth for fear or just
for, you know, trying to be nice or
whatever the case is. There's something
that happens with staff satisfaction
surveys that people just feel like they
can't be truthful. When I have spoken to
HR directors, some of them know this and
some of them don't or they're just
ignoring it and they want to just the
ones who don't are the ones who are
ignoring it. They're the ones who just
want to think that everything is going
swimmingly at the organization. If you
have anybody who says to you, whether
it's a CEO or an HR director or what
have you, that says people here aren't
burnt out, they're completely out of
touch with reality. They have absolutely
no idea what's going on with their
staff. If you look at big surveys across
the globe, it looks that there's about
75% of people who would say that they
feel burnt out. So, if your staff
satisfaction surveys aren't showing
those numbers, then there's something
that's going on either with the question
in the way that it was asked, the people
who don't feel safe talking about it or
something else. But a CEO's reaction to
whatever is being said on those metrics
needs to be really looked at with a fi
fine tooth comb to say what's actually
happening beneath the surface because
when we look at why people leave their
jobs, it's often times because of their
boss. And you talked about looking at
the middle the middle stuff. To me, team
trust is not built in big moment.
There's not a moment where you as an
employee walk into a meeting and say,
"Okay, great. I feel so much trust for
this team and my leaders." That just
doesn't happen. Trust is built in many,
many small ways by repetitive actions
that your leaders are taking. So if your
leader is just not even visible on the
floors of that hospital, if they're not
in it with the doctors and nurses and
everybody else who's making the
hospitals function, if they have no clue
because they're not really roaming
around and seeing it firsthand, then
again, they're going to be completely
out of touch with what's actually
happening inside of their organization.
So unless you are actually conversing
with the people who work there and
really caring about what they're saying
and doing something to address their
concerns, then your obliviousness is
going to cause the burnout to rise in
the organization. And I think a lot of
people underestimate the power that the
leaders in the company have. So, even if
the kind of organization might have a
culture of, okay, don't work when you're
off work, but then you've got people who
are texting you asking you questions
about previous patients or whatever else
while you're off work. What kind of
message is that sending? It's usually
from a superior, too, who might have
questions about something that they're
talking to you on your time off. So,
it's this these mixed signals that can
be given to folks to say, "Oh, we care
about you and we want you to have time
off and we understand that this job is
really hard." But then people sometimes,
unfortunately, break boundaries. And
what happens is that these workers then
just keep their heads down. They do
their job. They respond to their leader
who is texting them off hours and that's
it. And and so when the these people
stop talking, that's when the system
really starts breaking down,
but it happens first with the
relationship between a supervisor and
supervise.
Yeah, I I actually had a conversation at
one point with an executive. I just I
admired the guy. I didn't work for him
myself at the time, but I just asked
him. It was like he always seemed to be
telling stories about his kids. He's,
you know, doing things with them all the
time. They're very active. Um but really
really successful guy. He was at a very
high level in the company. And I I said,
'What what is what is it that you do
that really kind of kind of protects
that time? And he said, "Well, I mean, I
have a demanding job, but you know,
there's a start and stop time on my my
day and my phone, and once that time
comes, it gets shut off and put away."
He said, 'If everyone's asleep and I got
things I'm thinking about, I might draft
a few emails, but I don't send them
until the morning because I know if
people get an email from me, they're
going to like jump out of bed and go do
it. And I thought that was profound. And
my boss was sitting the other side of me
and I just asked if I handled things the
way he's handling it, would I still be
employed? And I was told, no. But it the
exact kind of scenario where these
expectations are are there. And we don't
realize how easily we start to concede
on boundaries. Um, and that would be a
whole a whole conversation unto itself,
I imagine. I mean, I'd love to hear your
thought on that. And and you know, how
can leaders be be more intentional about
encouraging their their teams in a way
because I mean, let's face it, any
company's going to take as much as you
want to give them.
Yes. Um, I think here is where I would
say that there's some generational
differences that come into play, too.
because what you just described with
your friend is easier for an executive
to make those boundaries and keep them
than it is for an entry-level worker.
So, there's a huge gap between the
privilege of being able to decide, oh,
I'm not going to work at 505 versus
somebody who's new to the organization.
And it truly is looked at like that. it
is looked at that the people who are
higher up do have more privilege and are
able to keep their boundaries more. What
you're seeing now, especially with Gen X
is that they are really starting to and
Gen Z, they're really starting to say,
you know what, I've got some serious
needs and I'm going to make these needs
known to you. And if you as a leader can
recognize those needs and do something
about them and meet them where they're
at and what they're asking from you,
then great. I think that there's been a
shift in the culture in the last 15
years or so with people actually feeling
like they can voice their concerns, but
again, it really depends on the
organization and their own psychological
safety of feeling like they can tell
their supervisor what it is that they
need. I mean, it's great for your friend
who's making time for his family and not
sending emails at certain times, but
that doesn't always work for people
because they might feel that if they do
get an email, like you was saying,
people might jump out of bed and and
they really feel like they need to
respond to it right away just because of
the power dynamic. That's something that
goes unressed, too. And it is another
reason that people need managerial
training because they don't recognize
that there's even a power dynamic that
exists. And I'm talking about senior
leaders just thinking, "Oh, well, if
this is what I say and this is how I
act, then everybody else is going to
follow in line." And it's like, "No,
that's not that's not true because you
can't be friends with them. You can't if
you're somebody superior, then they're
always going to be looking at you as if
you have more power than them." And so
that creates this very strange dynamic
where the supervisor or maybe the CEO
thinks that they are modeling this
behavior that everybody else wants to
latch on to but in reality people who
are down below are seeing it and saying
no I couldn't try that because of my
position in the organization not being
as important or my work not being as
important. So there is a divide. Yeah,
I've I've made mistakes so many times.
Eventually, I stopped beating my head
against the wall because I realized I
felt better when I didn't do that. But
it but it was really that that that
boundary setting cuz when particularly
when you change jobs, you want to make
an impact and you know, you just it's
just very very easy to very slow slowly.
It's like bo a frog being boiled to
death because they just think it's warm.
It's it's the same scenario. You start
to make those decisions one at a time
and before you know it, I mean, you're
you're getting burnt out because you and
it's not anyone else's fault. You know,
often times it's just we've not done a
good job even setting our own boundaries
um in a reasonable manner. I mean, I
think it's it's probably one of the
reasons that people struggle when
they're growing their career and there's
family dynamics and they're trying to
balance all that and human beings need
attention. They they just do and and
sometimes priorities get kind of messed
up, you know, with because people are so
motivated to to be successful in their
career. But I'd love to if if you could
you could have met me when I was going
through that, what would it be some of
the things that you would you would say
to me because I I know there's a lot of
people out there that are early in their
careers. They're going through some
pretty significant shifts and they they
could make some of these same mistakes.
But I mean, what would you say to
somebody like me early in my career like
that? The first thing that was coming up
for me is you've got to understand
what's inside and what's outside of your
control. And I think so many people
create scenarios in their heads and
therefore then let them get bogged down
by these scenarios that are completely
not in their control. So even doing some
sort of a ven diagram or or something
where you're getting it out on paper and
you're recognizing this is in my
control, this is not. and being able to
say, "Okay, well, so the things that are
in my control, what are the steps that I
can take?" Even if it's the most it's
the smallest step you can think of, it
doesn't matter. But what's the smallest
step you can take to get closer to what
it is you want the outcome to be for
them. And with all the things that are
not within your control, you got to let
them go. And this goes back to the need
for coaching and the individual being
recognized because we do not go to
confidence school. We don't go to any
sort of workshop or anything else. They
don't typically say, "Okay, now you've
got a new job. Now you've got to go do
12 weeks of coaching." If it were my
company, that's what I would have people
do. But it's because you have to manage
this stuff on an individual level. So,
what I would have told you back then is,
look, Chris, there's going to be lots of
things that are going to be completely
outside of your control in this job.
Even if you think you want to set a
boundary, you might not be able to
because of the confines of what that job
actually is. But let's talk about the
things that you can control. And there
are so many people who take home work
after they're done with their work for
the day. They close their computer and
they continue thinking about it. They
continue talking about it. It becomes
the conversation at the dinner table.
Why are we doing that? Why can we not
give ourselves a break from the thing
that we're being paid to do versus the
thing that we want to be doing like
spending time with our family? And so I
think, you know, the conversation at the
dinner table would be an example of
something that you do have control in.
And with you taking very small actions,
as as counterintuitive as this might
seem, the smallest actions end up really
becoming big ideas and big changes in
you as a person to be able to shift your
mindset and therefore lead a happier and
healthier life. But if you don't if you
don't take the time to make the small
changes, then your life is going to
continue as status quo and you're not
going to be happy and healthy because
all you're doing is thinking and talking
about work. So I think like I think a
lot of people they underestimate how
much power they actually can have with
the things that they're thinking about
and talking about, especially outside of
work and how they're talking to
themselves. The amount of negative
thoughts that we have that go around our
brains every single day is absurd. It's
absurd. It's around 90% of our thoughts
are negative. And if you can think about
times when you've talked to yourself in
ways that you would never talk to a
child, for example, by saying maybe,
"Oh, I'm so stupid." Or, "That was so
dumb. How could I have done that?" You
know, common things that people might
say to themselves. And then you say,
"Would I say that to a sevenyear-old or
a 10-year-old?" And you would not talk
to kids the same way that you talk to
yourself. So how does that over time
impact us as as just humans who are
trying to do the best that we can? It
has a humongous impact. So again, by
changing the small things, by changing
those moments where we start to really
berate ourselves and turn it into
something else, we're building new
habits, new neural pathways that will
allow us to be better people to
ourselves. That's where it all starts.
We can't be a great leader to a team if
we can't be a great leader to oursel.
And it has to begin there. And
organizations need to understand that
because burnout is something that only
happens because of work. You do not get
burnt out from your personal life. You
might use other words, you might have
other feelings, but the burnout in in
and of itself, the World Health
Organization classifies it as an
occupational phenomenon. So because it's
a workplace issue, it requires a
workplace solution. But that solution is
about the individual, not about the
whole entire company. you know that that
number is staggering to be and I guess
we all had have a sense that we do have
negative thoughts a lot but I didn't
realize it was 90%. That's that's a
staggering number and a really good
reason to make sure these kind of
conversations are happening.
This is
it is and if it'll be even more
staggering if I tell you the studies
have shown that there's about you have
about 60,000 thoughts a day. So if you
take 90% of 60,000 it's about 48,000
negative thoughts that you're having
every day. So what does that do to us as
a society when people are walking down
the street, walking into the office or
healthcare setting or whatever they're
walking into and this is the voice that
they have going on in their head.
I mean and the only person who can
change that is that person. Right.
Right. And we we do things to subject
ourselves to fueling that as well.
Whether it's social media, the news, I
mean, there's so many different things
that just constantly are be feeding that
pattern. It's we have to do things on
purpose to to break that or you know,
it's it's not a happy life if if you
can't find those ways to release it. And
I I love that you're talking about it
because I hope people are hearing this
because you're not weird. You're not,
you know, some rare person that's
dealing with all this stuff. We're all
dealing with it. We are you. It's just
as that's that's human nature. We're all
we've all got to, you know, learn how to
manage these things.
Yeah. And I think that that's why the
team approach that I do with teams and
organization works so much because when
they get into a room with other people
for 12 weeks on the 75 minutes that I
have with them,
the titles go away. That's the only
place where then over time, it does take
a couple weeks where people start to
feel like they can be vulnerable, like
they can be honest, like they're not
just answering a question on a staff
satisfaction survey that nobody really
cares about.
It's a place where they can see the
humanity in the other people and start
to empathize with them as their boss, as
their colleague, as another person. And
it's only truly in that when we can
start to see the goodness, beauty,
dignity, and worth in the other person
sitting on the Zoom screen across from
us that we can start to change our
reality. We can start to change our team
and the company and the way we treat
patients. And all of that
again goes back to our ability to
empathize, which is something AI cannot
do.
We're coming up on time. I can't believe
how quickly it flies. I I really enjoy,
you know, hearing your perspectives and
and what you what you're saying. I mean,
I'm learning a lot already for myself.
So, if if no one else ever listens to
this, I don't think that's going to be a
problem, but I'm learning. So, I really
appreciate it. I I want to just have you
talk just a little bit before we get
into the
looking out to the to the future and,
you know, some some interesting uh
thoughts I'm sure that you have about
where we're headed, what we need to be
doing, right? like right now. Uh but
maybe talk a little bit about, you know,
what what it would look like for an
executive who really wants to um really
wants to engage with you after hearing,
you know, your approach and
understanding there's some dynamics that
they really don't have a handle on. What
would an engagement look like and and
you know, how I mean, obviously the
organizations are different, but maybe
just talk to talk what that would look
like for an executive team.
Sure. Well, because the the 12-week
program works so well in reducing
burnout and really preventing burnout,
preventing people from leaving, that's
what I'm focusing on now. So, it's a
12week program that's called the 5C
leadership performance system. I called
it a system because that's what it is.
It's not just conversations. It's not
just feel-good pat yourself on the back
workshops. It is a system in order to
give people a unified language for them
to start thinking differently. and that
ends up impacting themselves and the
whole team and there's data to back that
up. So that is primarily what I'm doing.
So if people wanted to engage with me, I
would be happy to have a conversation
with them to see if it's the right fit
for their organizations. Honestly, the
only people that are going to end up
saying yes, this is the right fit for us
is if they have leaders that actually
get it and if they have leaders that
understand the ROI that comes from doing
things like this is just massive. It is
such a better return on investment for
people to invest now before people are
completely burnt out or when they're
just starting to create a team. Maybe
it's a s series A that's just starting
and they don't have it together yet.
This is the perfect kind of time where
people can say, "Okay, what can I do in
order to create the leadership culture
that I want here?" And if they think
it's just going to happen, there will be
a culture that happens, good, bad, or
indifferent. And so if they want some
sort of control over what their vision
is, then it's a great thing for them to
invest in. So just going back to the
ROI, I mean, you take the fact that if
you can prevent one single person from
leaving the organization and walking out
with that institutional knowledge, it
will be way less money for them to work
with me than it would be for them to
lose somebody else. Um, so that's
primarily what I'm doing. If I do have a
couple of clients that are just
one-on-one and those are usually CEOs,
executive directors of the like some
sort of senior leadership role that is a
lot more one-on-one
really deep kind of going into their
beliefs and how they're limiting
themselves in whatever it is that they
want. If they want to be the leader that
they have in their minds, a lot of times
people can use a thought partner for
that. So that's what a coach does. is a
coach doesn't give their opinion. A
coach really just helps people by asking
them questions and helping them figure
out their own answers. And so that's
what I like about it. It's not
consulting in that sense. It really is
just let's get in on a call and talk
this through and I can be a sounding
board, but you're going to be the one to
figure it out. And that's why they
actually change. That's why it's
sustainable. That's why there's science
to back up what coaching actually is and
does because it's the person making
their own changes. It's not me saying
this is what you should do.
So, I'm happy to have people go to my
website and and they can find more
information about what I'm talking about
there. But I really think that this is
maybe I'm biased, but I don't think I
am. I really think this is the best
investment that any organization could
invest in for their team because it will
make everybody love their job that much
more, which will help profits, it will
help care, it will help whatever kind of
outcomes you're looking for. It all
starts with your employees. No,
I I really appreciate you saying that
and they're they're listening. Look,
I'll make sure that all all of this
material will be available to you in the
show notes. she'll know how to get get
in touch with Carly. And if you're a CEO
and you're, you know, maybe not really
sure if you're getting this getting this
the the straight talk that you need,
maybe maybe a a phone call or an email
to to connect with Carly would would be
a a really good good move for you to
make to really start to make sure that
you're you're getting the getting the
right story and you're you're moving
moving in a positive direction with your
team. because we're we're in a time
where trust is going to be
the thing that makes or breaks us as we
go through these kind of
transformations. I mean, it's it's clear
there's a lot of lines being drawn and
some of the technology companies are
going so fast and they don't care if it
we're we're ready for it from a
governance or any other perspective
frankly. So, you know, leaders need to
take advantage of the opportunities
while they have them and they can get
some some good good advice and and learn
some skills to really help your
organization. I I'd encourage you to do
that. As we kind of lying down there,
there's a couple questions I I'd like to
to ask you. First, I mean, if you could
change that assumption that leaders are
making right now about their workforce,
is there something that stands out in
your mind? What that would be?
Yes. The assumption that I would change
for leaders to stop making about their
workforce is that they're okay. They're
not okay. Everything about the world is
not okay for anybody who is working for
corporate America right now. It is a
very wild time and most people are in
survival mode. So, their brains are not
even functioning properly because
they're kind of going to this primitive
place of how do I just keep my paycheck?
and they're not being able to be even
creative or calm because they're just so
focused on the stress. So, yeah, the the
incorrect assumption would be that your
people are okay. They're not.
I guess I wrap things up. I I'd love to
know if if you had a a bold prediction
about 2026, whether it's in the
workforce space, whether it's AI
related, you know, one of the themes
that obviously I like to talk about is
picking up the signal through the noise
and there's a lot of noise. Maybe maybe
highlight one or two things that that
you think we should be looking for,
maybe even leaning into a bit if we can.
I think for me what comes up two things.
Number one is there's a lot of noise
with AI and I know that this podcast
talks about it all the time and I know
that people are constantly just
comparing notes on which AI to use. All
of that is true and at the same time it
goes back to what I said at the very top
of the podcast of you can't replace
human connection and we all need human
connection. So my prediction is actually
that AI will push us back towards human
relationships and focusing on seeing
each other more on picking up the phone
more on stopping with just having
everything be in text and it will really
kind of make us do a full circle of oh
actually now I understand why it's so
much better to be in a room with people
than on a screen or now I understand why
It's so much easier to not have conflict
with my boss when I talk to her on the
phone as opposed to via email. And so I
think that we're kind of going through
this test of time to say, "Hey, we've
got all these tools to kind of put in
your face to show you that nothing can
replace humanto human connection." That
would be the first thing. This is one of
the reasons I was so excited to have you
come on and I'm I I am going to do
everything I could do to make sure that
your voice is out there is what you're
saying is really important. You your
your voice is an important one for
people to be listening to. I I can't
thank you enough for for coming on the
show and being willing to have this kind
of conversation with me. It's it's it's
very timely. It's very very much needed
and I I look forward to to seeing your
your continued success and I I know your
business will will thrive and I I can't
wait to hear u more success stories.
There's there's a lot more people that
will be benefiting once they uh once
they hear what you have to say, once
they engage with you. So, thank you so
much for being on the Signar Room and I
can't wait to hear from you again. What
what what's going to be going on? um
probably have to have you back on
because I know that we didn't scratch
the surface of some things that we
probably need to talk about. This is not
about technology. To your your point, it
really is about people and
relationships.
Thank you so much. It was such a
pleasure and I wish you all the best as
well and continued success with the
signal room.
Thank you. That's it for this episode of
the Signal Room. If today's conversation
sparked something in you, an idea, a
challenge or a perspective worth
amplifying, I'd love to hear from you.
Message me on LinkedIn or visit
cigarroompodcast.com
to explore being a guest on an upcoming
episode. Until next time, stay tuned,
stay curious, and stay human.